TYPHOON FAMILY
Ms. Oh!
-Mr. Go!
-My gosh, Mr. Go!
-Okay.
-What do we do?
-We get it.
-Ms. Oh! Please help…
Don't give up on me!
-Let's go!
-Help me!
-Wait…
I'm innocent!
-Mr. Go…
-I'm not guilty!
Man, why are the roaches here so big?
-Do we have the number?
-Yes, I had it written down.
Where is it?
KOREAN EMBASSY
-Look, here.
-Is this it?
Hello, this is the Korean Embassy
in Thailand. How can I help you?
Hello, we are a company
called Typhoon Trading from Korea.
One of my staff
is being held at the detention center.
Okay, what was the reason
for their detention?
I hear it's for bribery,
but the sum was almost nothing.
Did you bribe an official?
I understand, but it's just $50.
Please contact the embassy
only in urgent situations.
Yes, that's exactly
the kind of situation we're in.
If it was just $50,
they'll be released soon.
A criminal offence…
Why did you hang up?
What did they say?
-The cold hard truth.
-What?
Oh, gosh.
I shouldn't have given him that money.
WE ARE OPEN
About my uncle.
He's bald and bold.
Can you believe he filled half that bag
with his care package for Ma-yong?
Mind you, that's a huge suitcase
expats use to travel.
I'm back at my old company.
I'm really determined…
to give it my all this time.
So, don't you worry about me.
Okay, then.
I'll get going now.
What is it?
I can't believe it. Not again.
Take it.
You'll have to treat Ma-yong
to a meal or something.
That's how you win goodwill.
This is the first US dollar bill
I've ever held in my hand.
Thanks to you, son.
SHOE REPAIR SPECIALIST
OPEN DAILY FROM 7:00 A.M. TO 6:00 P.M.
That bill meant so much to me.
You must be Korean.
What was that?
I worked in Korea for four years
in Gwangju, Gyeonggi-do.
You seem like an upstanding guy.
How did you end up here?
Well, I'm in for bribery.
You bribed someone?
-Who?
-A customs officer at Lamchaya Port.
By the way, how old are you
to talk so casually to me?
I'm 48 years old. I'm old enough.
A customs officer at Lamchaya Port.
What did he just say?
-There will be a trial early tomorrow.
-A trial? All right.
-It's for those who bribed a small amount.
-A small amount. Got it.
As in any payments under $200.
Under $200? Of course, I should've known.
It made no sense
to get dragged here for chump change.
I'll be released tomorrow then.
What's your name? My name is Go Ma-jin.
I'm Somchai. Somchai Saroon.
Somchai? Your name reminds me of som tam.
Hang in there, all right?
I like your style.
You think I've got style?
I guess you like my jacket.
This is my everyday look.
Anyway, it's a pleasure.
Things will turn around,
so don't ever lose your spirit.
I can rest easy now.
I'm going to sleep.
Jeez.
I'm getting out.
Gosh.
Tomorrow?
Thank goodness.
The newly elected governor
made a thorough sweep
to stamp out corruption
in the local government.
Still, any bribe under 10,000 baht
is seen as a misdemeanor
and can receive a summary judgment.
He'll likely be released
with a fine at most.
How much would the fine be?
Around 100,000 baht,
so about 3,000,000 won.
By the way,
what about the meeting with Nihakham Group
as our potential client?
I don't think you can
make a comeback from today's mishap.
-What?
You see, this incident made the headlines
of every newspaper and news show.
What's more, Chairman Nihakham
is a stickler for rules.
Oh, dear.
The whole thing has turned
into a pain in the neck, hasn't it?
It's not so dire.
Once Mr. Go is released
and we get our goods,
we can sell them, right?
-Bangkok has six million residents!
-That's true.
We can sell our goods.
Are you okay?
Goodness.
I'd say you seem pretty agitated.
What?
No, it was nothing. You can sit back down.
-Come on, it's hard to look up at you.
-Calm down and take a seat, Mr. Kang.
Hey, I got it!
Five times one is five
Five times two is ten
Attaboy. Keep it going.
Five times three is fifteen
Five times four is twenty
Five times five is…
What's five times five?
Five times five…
Five times five is 35!
From the top.
I thought the department store
doesn't open today.
Has your older sister given you a call…
I guess she hasn't.
Well…
This is… You know, take them.
What was that? I didn't catch that at all.
-What are those?
-A present for me.
-Let me do it, ma'am.
-What?
Thanks.
Why did you bring out
the heavy comforters for winter?
They're cotton-filled comforters
to keep my grandchildren warm.
I'm sure I still have a long time
to stay on this earth,
but I always feel like
I'm on a tight schedule.
There we go.
Let's start.
MOMO'S PUB
Come on in.
Welcome.
Here. Please take a seat.
I brought a lunchbox.
I've never done this before.
-Is this for me?
-You can have it all.
Thank you.
The place looks different during the day.
Didn't you say you run the place
with your mother?
My dear Ms. Kim Eul-nyeo owns this place,
but she's been away often lately.
I guess she's busy.
I can't say.
-How long do you work daily?
-Me?
We keep the place open for ten hours.
With ingredient prep and cleaning,
I work about 12 to 13 hours.
Business hasn't been so great,
so I might have to pick up other jobs.
-Other jobs?
-Yes.
By the way, with a business of this size,
doesn't that mean the owner is well-off?
Since this is your mother's place,
you're her heir.
Hey, you're rich, Nam-mo.
My dear Mi-ho, you'll probably swoon
if you meet an actually rich person.
Don't be silly.
I've met plenty of rich people!
Really?
You know what?
You're so pretty.
Give me a second.
I'll whip up a tasty snack.
Where are his suitcases?
Let's get him some clothes to change into
after his release tomorrow.
He only had an undershirt
underneath the jacket.
Okay.
Hey, the collar is all stretched.
-That even has a hole.
-That too.
Jeez, Mr. Go enjoyed a snack all alone.
SPICY TUNA
Mr. Kang.
Look.
KIMCHI RAMYUN, NEMO RAMYUN,
BRAVO TUNA, SPICY TUNA
He packed more to share with us.
He brought three items each.
MIN BURI CRIMINAL COURT
MIN BURI CIVIL COURT
I don't get it.
-Why can't we go in?
-Be patient, Mr. Kang.
We're looking into it.
Hey, there's Ha-neul.
Get over here.
-Be careful.
-Let's see.
"Ten thousand dollars"?
It says you bribed $10,000, not $50.
What? They think Mr. Go did that?
Wait, $10,000 equals over 15 million won.
I don't get it, either.
That must be why Ma-jin
wasn't included in the trial.
How did $50 turn into $10,000, anyway?
Look, the officer's testimony
is right here.
"At 6:00 p.m. on April 27th,
a Korean man gave me 10,000 dollars
on my way home after work."
After work? But we were there in daytime.
I saw it happen. This is not right.
I'm telling you,
I saw him give the 50 dollars.
This must be why Ma-jin
is getting a full trial.
Ha-neul, when's his trial?
It says "the day after tomorrow."
Look, Mr. Kang.
This must be why
we haven't received your helmets.
The authorities have seized them
instead of clearing them.
What happens then?
If you fail to explain,
they'll throw them out right away.
They'll destroy them.
-That means we have 48 hours.
-Why do you keep speaking English?
So, what now? We've got to find a way out.
Everything's gone downhill.
Wait, that's Mr. Go's jacket.
Where did you get this jacket?
I'm asking where you got this jacket.
I don't know any Korean guy.
-Hey!
-Stop!
Hold on. Let me explain.
Something's fishy.
How did he know Mr. Go is a Korean?
-Hey, no, you're a foreigner.
-Okay!
-All right, but--
-Stop it!
Listen, Mr. Kang.
"Friends?" They've come to see me?
I'm too ashamed to face them.
What's going on with the helmets?
Hang on.
For just one minute.
Just for a second or one minute.
What do we do
if Mr. Go ends up serving time?
-I hear life in prison is brutal here.
-Let's wait it out, Mr. Kang.
-Let's not go there just yet.
-Excuse me.
Here, sir.
Thank you.
-Let's go.
-Hey, Mr. Kang.
-Mr. Go!
-Where is he?
Where is he?
-Hey, Mr. Go!
-There he is.
-Where?
-Over there. Mr. Go!
Mr. Go! We're over here!
-We're here.
-Mr. Go!
-We're right here, Mr. Go!
-Over here, Mr. Go!
-Ms. Oh!
Mr. Kang!
Mr. Go!
Where's your top?
I mean, what happened to your jacket?
I don't know. Someone must've stolen it.
I look awful, don't I?
No, you don't.
You look like your usual self.
You seem fine.
Hang in there, Mr. Go.
Have you had anything to eat?
I'm going to eat when I get released!
We've only got five minutes left.
Reassure him or something, Mr. Kang.
Mr. Go!
We'll get you out of there!
Don't worry about a thing.
What about the deal?
Don't stress about it!
It's all going to be fine.
Don't you worry about me.
I served in the Marines, dang it!
All right. Don't you worry about us.
We'll get you out no matter what.
-I'll be fine here.
-Make sure to eat, okay?
Don't forget to feed yourself!
-Keep your belly full, okay?
-I'll be fine!
Off you go.
Hey, Mi-seon!
Ms. Oh!
-Why does he want me?
-Let's get over there.
-I'm right here, Mr. Go.
-Ms. Oh!
-What's wrong?
-Mi-seon!
I'm here, Mr. Go.
-Pick it up!
-Wait.
No! Off you go.
I got it. Don't worry.
All right. See you.
Make sure to eat, okay?
Don't skip a meal. Sit tight.
-I'll keep this safe.
-Okay.
Make sure to eat, Mr. Go.
Okay.
-Okay.
-Eat well!
-Get out!
-Hang in there!
MANAGE OUR CLIENTS, SALES
AND INVENTORY - YOUR SENIOR COLLEAGUE
Manage…
our clients, sales and inventory.
Your senior colleague.
"Clients, sales and inventory."
Those are the basics of sales.
The basics of sales?
Does it make you that happy?
It says "your senior colleague," Mr. Kang.
I now have a colleague,
not just someone who bosses me around.
Ms. Oh.
What are the basics of being a CEO?
Excuse me?
You now have
the three basic items to manage.
But for me,
I don't know what I should manage.
What would my father tell me to protect?
The company, of course.
Mr. Kang!
What about the deal?
Don't stress about it!
Don't you worry about me.
I served in the Marines, dang it!
Take care then.
EPISODE 9
WALKING TO THE SKY
Mr. Go!
Don't forget to feed yourself!
Keep your belly full, okay?
Are we still knee deep in the Korean War?
Why is she so hung up on food?
Mr. Go!
We'll get you out of there!
Don't worry about a thing.
That's the least I can do here.
I'm the one who messed up.
You two are pretty chummy, aren't you?
I get it, but let me share.
Excuse me. Coming through.
-Sorry.
-Come help me out later.
Of course. I'll see you soon!
Excuse me. Coming through.
Oh, dear. Sorry about that.
Please excuse me.
Coming through.
Hello, sir.
-Hey, keep it up.
-Thank you.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Hey.
I'm fine.
All newbies flounder on their first day.
The work itself isn't hard.
Everybody else works for a living too.
Go easy, will you?
Okay. I'll page you when I clock out.
All right. Make sure to do that.
Mi-ho. Don't you worry about me.
Me, worried? You got it all wrong.
Sure. Just don't push yourself too far.
All right. See you.
Kisses.
Hey, new guy.
-Did you say you can ride a motorcycle?
-Yes.
Do a quick delivery for me.
Sure.
Are you okay?
Give me my money back.
Who did this? What the hell is this?
-What on earth…
-What a bunch of rascals.
-I invested a heavy sum. What do I do now?
-Let's leave now.
What do I do?
How could this have happened?
-I'm penniless now.
-I can't believe this.
What do I do about the lost money?
That money was my lifeline!
Oh, dear. We're done for.
-Get over here quickly.
-What I wouldn't do to those crooks!
How could the heavens allow this?
Where would these bastards be holed up?
-They took off with everything.
-That money was everything to me.
How dare you take my precious money,
you rotten bastards?
Those bastards…
-How am I supposed to go on?
-What…
My heart is breaking.
What should I do now?
-Give me my money back.
-Oh, all my money…
This can't be true!
-Drink some.
-I will.
You offered my company
an invaluable opportunity.
My foolishness almost caused
you and your company harm.
My sincerest apologies.
I'm glad you know of your foolishness.
But I don't need your apology.
In business,
what you need is
not an apology, but money.
It's much better
to hold onto feces than a fart.
The saying that it's better to be
holding onto something substantial,
even if it may seem useless.
I wanted to ask you something.
Why Thailand?
I've always wondered if a quality product
would have a universal appeal.
Price concerns aside,
if the helmets sell here,
I can look forward to future opportunities
in the Thai market.
However, I can't work with a company
that's caused problems.
Thanks for your efforts.
Tae-poong.
Well, no.
Forget about opportunities and insights.
We're here to sell the helmets.
-Go ask her to take some off our hands.
-What?
It looks like she has a soft spot for you.
Go on and put your skills to good use.
-My skills?
-You know what I'm talking about.
Tell her she's pretty
and write "wish coupon" on her palm.
Go and chat with her
before she leaves for her meal.
This is it. She's on her way.
Where are you going?
Come on, why are you leaving?
-Get in here already.
-But still…
Fine.
I don't go around
telling people they're pretty.
There we go. One, two.
What's that?
-Is it a gift for me?
-Yes.
Inside are items from the US
for potential future projects.
Really?
Hang on, who's Katherine Kang?
Oh, that's Aunt Kang Suk-ja in LA.
I can't wait.
What's this? Does she take me
for a common peddler?
Does she seriously
expect me to sell these?
All this common stuff?
I can't believe this.
What even is this mess?
A shirt.
How unsophisticated.
Jeez.
That aside, why did that idiot,
Tae-poong, fly to Thailand?
Oh, he went to Thailand
to export Korean helmets.
He sure loves safety gear and shit.
Enough about him.
What should I do?
Why won't my dad make any investments?
Why did he have to kick up the dust
about buying those expensive ships?
He drives me insane.
Wait, Mr. Ha.
What does my dad have
against Typhoon Trading?
As for me,
I want Tae-poong ruined for getting
in my way ever since we were eight.
I just don't understand it.
Don't you find it odd?
The company didn't have much.
I wouldn't dare to presume
what your father might be thinking,
but he has no interest
in such a trifling company.
Goodness, it's late.
I should return to my office.
TYPHOON TRADING
EMPLOYMENT RECORD CARD
CHA SEON-TAEK
OH MI-SEON
KOO MYUNG-GWAN
That's more like it.
We could use an insurance of sorts.
BAE SONG-JUNG
GO MA-JIN
Your son has asked me
about the Typhoon Trading business.
Hyun-jun doesn't need to know, does he?
-Understood.
-Dad!
I found it, Dad.
I did it.
Dad.
Look.
Why don't I try selling this?
What do you think? Isn't it awesome?
Have you given a thought
to how you would sell it?
Why would I bother with that?
You brought in eggheads
and pay them a fortune to sort that out.
Even so,
the final call is your responsibility.
TYPHOON TRADING
EMPLOYMENT RECORD CARD
Are you sure you're not hungry?
I have no appetite.
Have you called your family?
No.
You know,
Tae-poong…
Are we finally on a first-name basis?
Unbelievable.
Are you still mad?
I'm sorry.
I was too focused on securing a deal
as a sales representative.
I wish you'd pay more attention
to how I'd feel.
Wait a moment.
Hello.
Could I have two watermelon smoothies?
Sure, just a moment.
Here, drink this.
This is watermelon juice.
It's sweet.
Even when we're worried sick,
we shouldn't skip a meal.
Come on, I'm not worried sick.
I didn't know you could make juice
out of watermelon.
It's amazing.
Mi-ho loves watermelons.
Do you miss her?
You should give her a call.
Don't worry about the phone bill.
Tell you what.
I've never stayed apart
from my family before.
So, I miss Beom dearly
and wonder how Mi-ho is doing.
My grandmother has been on my mind too.
But I actually find this freeing.
Now that I'm alone, I feel like
a weight has been lifted off my chest.
The idea of a business trip
excited me as well.
Maybe that's why I insisted on coming,
even when I knew Mr. Go hated it.
I'm a terrible person, aren't I?
Sure, you're awful. What a surprise.
Still, I like it.
When you're being mean.
Think about it.
A person can't be good all the time.
Anyone would think
someone is a nice person
if they are good 70% of the time
and bad 30% of the time.
But you're mean only 10% of the time,
which was on this trip.
You think I'm a wimp, don't you?
You are…
brilliant.
Out of all the people I've met,
you're the coolest…
and the prettiest.
Aren't you lucky
to have me crushing on you?
Don't you want to?
Come on, Mr. Kang!
You're being silly.
This isn't the time for this.
What are you objecting to?
Don't get so up close and personal.
-Why not?
-I don't feel comfortable.
You don't feel comfortable?
At any rate,
Mr. Go is facing possible jail time.
We shouldn't be wasting our time
on our personal matters.
We've got a serious situation here.
By the way, why do you think
the customs officer falsely accused Mr. Go
of paying him $10,000?
He must've wanted
to get someone else off the hook.
Mr. Go's bribe was only about $50.
Could the officer have lied to get the man
with Mr. Go's jacket released?
We don't know
how he got hold of that jacket,
but he must've pretended to be Mr. Go.
Mr. Go's trial is tomorrow.
I'll have to secure the money
to pay his bail.
Do we have enough funds, though?
I've called colleagues in Korea
to gather what funds they can.
Let's do all we can
to get him out on bail tomorrow.
I should've done more to stop him
instead of taking photos.
Tell me. Did you really hate it?
Right, the photos!
Come on!
Here they are.
You finished two rolls of film
in that short time?
Three rolls, actually.
Each only had 24 shots, anyway.
We need the photos for our trip report.
I recorded pretty much
all the events of the day.
Records remain while memories fade.
Hey, that's a cool line.
It's what your father used to say.
I think I photographed the incident.
No, I'm sure of it.
Mr. Go handed over the cigarette packs
and slipped the 50-dollar bill inside.
I can't believe you took photos of that.
Why did you do it, though?
Because he went against the company code.
I see.
Where can we go to get these developed?
We can't wait around until tomorrow.
It's 9:30 p.m.
Mr. Go's trial is at 11:00 a.m. and
the helmets will be scrapped at 4:00 p.m.
We have to clear Mr. Go's name
before that, no matter what.
Let's go look for a photo studio.
-All right.
-Let's go.
-Where should we go?
-Over there, I suppose?
Hi. Hello.
-Well, photo…
-Photo… Print.
-Okay.
-Okay, thank you.
Like so…
Oh, no.
-We've got films here. We want photos.
-Photo films.
-Okay, thank you.
-Okay.
Gosh.
Where can we…
I don't see anything.
-Let's ask him and call it a day.
-Okay.
-Hi. Hello.
-Hello.
-Yes, photo and film.
-Oh, photo.
-Saphan? Bridge.
-Yes.
-Is there a studio?
-Just across the bridge.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
Hey, look over there!
It says "photo."
-Film… Look inside.
-Okay.
-Excuse me!
-Hello?
-Is anyone there?
-Please!
-Help me!
-I'm in a rush! Hello?
-Hello? Is no one there?
-Hello.
-No.
-Thank you.
-Wrong again.
Excuse me.
-Please.
-Excuse me.
Could you call the owner…
-Photo…
-I guess she doesn't run the studio.
-Dang, what do we do now?
-I'm losing my mind.
Maybe it's time for us to give up.
What can we do
when there are no photo studios?
We need to cause a scene
to have people call the studio owner.
-Shall I kick down the door?
-What?
-I'll do it.
-Hold on.
Let's think of another way. Don't.
They'll open the shop
if the police get here.
Don't do it. Give me a second.
This isn't the way. My gosh!
Seriously? Wait!
-Hello.
-Good evening.
-Could you open the door?
How long will it take?
-Three.
-Three hours?
-Three hours? Then…
That would be 2 a.m.
Will it be done by 2 a.m.?
-What did he say?
-No idea.
MAY 2ND, 1998
We have to wait until then?
A whopping three days? Three days?
Three days?
-Yes.
-No.
No, no.
One, two, three.
Forget it!
-Wait, wait.
-Hang on.
Okay.
Okay. So…
How much do you want?
We'll offer…
-There. 1,000 baht.
-Okay.
Thousand. 1,000 baht.
What? He struck off a day?
-There.
-Two thousand.
I can't believe this. So?
-Still not satisfied?
-Go, go, go, go.
He's driving me crazy.
What are you doing, Ms. Oh?
No, I can't lose this!
How come? Was it your father's?
I only brought one watch.
Take it off.
You know we haven't got time for this.
-But it's…
-Hurry!
Do we have a deal?
You can have this on top of 3,000 baht.
-Deal?
-Sure.
All right, sure.
Gosh, seriously?
What's this? Has the power gone out?
He turned the lights off
to get the photos developed.
Oh, right.
We're on the right track then.
What time is it, anyway?
I don't have my watch with me.
BELLUA DEPARTMENT STORE
CLEARANCE SALE
I guess he's not coming today.
Hey, you're here.
My shift ended later than usual.
I couldn't reach the department store
in time, so I came here.
Sorry.
Let's go. I'll walk you home.
Okay.
We're here already.
You must be tired. Go in and rest.
Hey.
-Yeah?
-What's the matter?
What's going on?
Mi-ho, it's just that…
This won't do.
Let me take a few more steps back.
My family had to close down the pub today.
Things somehow turned out that way.
We had to put our place on sale…
We'll probably have to crash
with my aunt for the time being.
And?
I just thought
I should tell you.
You're not supposed to keep a secret
from the person you're seeing.
And why did you step away to tell me that?
I didn't want my sorrow
to taint you.
You dummy.
Cut out the melodrama.
Just tell me it's rough for you.
Be frank and ask me to stay by your side.
Okay.
Look at these.
-Hey, we've got our photos.
-Yeah.
Thank goodness.
SAWADDEE
They'll be ready soon.
Meet me at the court.
I'll go get the money and the documents.
The money?
We don't know
how much the fine will be, so…
-Okay.
-Be careful on your way, all right?
-Sure. See you later.
-Okay.
Thank you.
MIN BURI CRIMINAL COURT
MIN BURI CIVIL COURT
Hey, there comes Ma-jin.
He looks better than I hoped.
By the way, where is Ms. Oh?
She should be here by now.
All rise.
You can sit back down now.
What do I do? Oh, no!
What should I do now?
Damn, you've got to be kidding me.
I deeply regret that,
as a foreign national,
you have attempted
to undermine the laws of this country.
While there is some dispute
regarding the amount of the bribe,
The ruling is based on the $10,000
stated in the witness's testimony.
So…
I'll talk to her.
"Evidence," so proof?
I don't have such a big sum…
Please ask her how I'm supposed
to prove that I'm broke.
Then, I will deliver the verdict.
We have evidence!
Could you interpret for me?
Even the total price of the helmets
we brought is nowhere near $10,000.
Why would we use that much for a bribe?
I also brought
the import declaration form
and the quotation we've sent
the Nihakham Group by fax.
What's more,
I have the purchase agreement.
You have a point.
But… this is insufficient
as direct evidence.
You may have had…
I think she's saying that the documents
don't qualify as conclusive proof.
More… So…
Well…
We…
How should I say this…
-Are you okay?
-The photos…
The photos fell under the bridge.
I tried to get them out of the water,
but all we've got are these films.
What do we do?
I'm sorry. I don't know what to do.
It's all good. You did a good job.
-Are you unhurt?
-Yes, I'm good.
What do we do? I'm so sorry.
Don't apologize.
We've got these, at least.
The film…
Turn the lights off on my signal, okay?
Okay.
What on earth?
I'd get 30 years, wouldn't I?
WALKING TO THE SKY
TYPHOON FAMILY
Our helmets will be disposed of
if this case isn't closed by 4:00.
It'll take at least an hour
to get to the port.
I have something to tell you.
Thank you.
I thought about it
and realized I never said this.
I was just doing my job,
whenever I had to do it.
-We aren't going to work?
-Well, we are.
But we aren't going in that direction.
This is Typhoon Trading version 2.0.
"Notice of Office Relocation."
I'll be back.
I promise.
Subtitle translation by: Jeongwoo Kim